Okechukwu Uchenna John

Software Engineer(NodeJS)

Lagos, Nigeria.

Email:

okechukwuchenna@gmail.com

Github:

https://github.com/uchennajohn

Mobile: +2349014214236

PROFILE

I am a purpose-driven and goal-oriented Software Developer with over 2 years experience who is open to learning and on a daily quest to make a better version of myself. I am passionate, possess an agile mindset, diligent and committed to achieving organizational goals and objectives and always provide solutions and never make excuses. A proactive and pragmatic individual with a good understanding of team collaboration to optimize productivity. I also have excellent communication skills that help me to be able to share my ideas and solutions and help me thrive as a team player in any organization.

EXPERIENCE

Decagon, Benin — Software Engineer(NodeJs)

September 2022 - Present

- Handled Database Management System with SQL like MySQL, PostgreSQL and NoSQL databases like MongoDB.
- Developed, tested and deployed software systems and full software lifecycle.
- GraphQL for API calls in applications.
- Created responsive front-end web application interfaces according to design guidelines and information architecture.
- Containerized application using Docker.
- Built scalable web application using Nodejs, Reactjs, ExpressJs, Typescript.

ATASoftec, Remote — Front-End Web Developer

December 2022 - Present

- Partnered in building a School Management System.
- Developed and tested REST APIs.

NHub Foundation, Jos — Front-End Web Developer

January 2021 - December 2021

- React.js framework to make reusable web components.
- Performed detailed code review and testing to improve code quality.

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS 3
- Javascript
- Typescript
- VanillaJS
- React
- React Native
- Nodeis
- Angular
- Material UI
- Bootstrap
- Rest API
- MongoDB
- PostgresQL
- GraphQL
- MySQL
- Docker
- QA Testing
- Scrum and Agile Methodology
- Version Control with Git and Github
- Tableau

Mounted Wings Cyber Tech, Makurdi — Mechatronic Engineer(Arduino)

January 2021 - December 2021

- Built a Self Driving Mini vacuum cleaner.
- Organized seminar for undergraduates to learn Arduino Programming and embedded systems.

EDUCATION

• Bachelor Of Engineering: Mechanical Engineering, Federal University of Agriculture, Makurdi, Benue State.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

- August, 2022, Scrum Fundamental Certified.
- April, 2022, Google Data Analytics Professional.
- April, 2021, Project Management Certification.
- July, 2019, FreeCodeCamp, Responsive Web Design.

PROJECTS

AnimaFarm:

Created an ecommerce application (as a part of a scrum core team) that connects livestock farmers to their potential buyers by providing them with virtual shops and easing commodity payment by incorporating payment gateway and provision for third party delivery/logistics services.

Technologies Implemented: NodeJs, ExpressJs, SQlite, ReactJS and Github.

CuisineRecipe:

Created an application where users can search for meals by ingredients used in cooking them. Users also go ahead to check the steps in preparing such a meal, basically, it fetches the data from a food API and renders it on the front end.

Technologies Implemented: HTML, CSS, Javascript and VanillaJS

Link: https://cuisinerecipie.netlify.app/

Github Repo:https://github.com/uchennajohn/FoodCuisineApp

Chat App

Part of a team of three Node developers that build a web real-time chat app, **Technologies Implemented:** NodeJS, Socket.io, ExpressJS, MongoDB and ReactJS

Bank App

Part of a team of three developers that built a web bank application with a simulated account summary graph showing income and expense over a period, transaction portal with a transaction history section, currency converter section and other functionalities.

Technologies implemented: React, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, JWT passport and Tokens, Bootstrap.

Food Vending App

Building a Food Vending Web Application where customers can view an array of virtual food outlets and purchase their favorite meal and get it delivered to them.

Technologies implemented: React, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, JWT passport and Tokens, Bootstrap.

Github Repo: https://github.com/uchennajohn/Food-App